A Guide to the Records and briefs of the Virginia Supreme Court, 1850-2016.
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Records and briefs of the Virginia Supreme Court,
1850-2016.
The Library of Virginia
35441, 35435, 35436, 35437, 35438, 35439, 41990, 42758, 42668, 42472, 43117, 43502, 43874, 44421, 50155, 50822, 51364, 51781, 53296
Virginia. Supreme Court.
718 cu.ft.
These records are part of the Virginia Supreme Court record group (R.G 100)
Acquisition Information
Accession 35435, 35436, 35437, 35439 and 35441 were transferred 1997 June 24; Accession 35776 was transferred 1998 March 25; Accession 41990 was transferred 2005 June 15; Accession 42472 was transferred 2007 January 27; Accession 42668 was transferred 2006 May 21; Accession 42758 was transferred 2006 July 21; Accession 43117 was transferred 2007 February 16; Accession 43502 was transferred 2007 October 30; Accession 43874 was transferred 2008 July 14; Accession 44421 was transferred 2009 July 28; Accession 50155 was transferred 2011 September 19; Accession 50822 was transferred 2013 March 28; Accession 51364 was transferred 2014 July 16; Accession 51781 was transferred 2016 April 25; Accession 53296 was transferred 2021 April 26.
Virginia. -- Supreme Court.
Virginia. -- Supreme Court of Appeals
Appellate courts -- Virginia.
Courts -- Virginia.
Briefs (legal documents) -- aat.
State government records -- Virginia. -- aat.
This series includes records and briefs for cases heard by the Supreme Court of Virginia. These records were filed with the Clerk of the Supreme Court and copies forwarded to each justice for review and study before the cases were argued. Types of records may include brief of appellant, brief of appellee, reply briefs, reply briefs cross appellant, amicus briefs, petitions, and appendices.
Accession 35776 is bound briefs and appendices, covering 1870 through 1968. All other accessions are loose briefs and appendices.
Related Material
Index available on the Library of Virginia website: Supreme Court Records and Briefs Database (index)
Contents List
- Supreme Court Accessions.
  - Accession 35435 (10 cu. ft.), 1982 Oct-1983 Apr.
  - Accession 35436 (34 cu. ft.), 1986 Jan-1988June.
  - Accession 35437 (5 cu. ft.), 1983 June-Nov.
  - Accession 35439 (13 cu. ft.), 1985 Apr-Nov.
  - Accession 35441 (315.35 cu. ft.), 1866-1980.
  - Accession 35776 (237 cu. ft.), 1867-1967.
  - Accession 41990 (6 cu. ft.), 2001-2003.
  - Accession 42472 (37 cu. ft.), 1985-1989.
  - Accession 42668 (217 cu. ft.), 1988-2004.
  - Accession 42758 (16 cu. ft.), 2001 Nov-2005 Nov.
  - Accession 43117 (12 cu. ft.), 2005-2006.
  - Accession 43502 (11 cu. ft.), 2006 June-2007 Jan.
  - Accession 43874 (13 cu. ft.), 2007 Jan-Sept.
  - Accession 44421 (13 cu. ft.), 2007 Nov-2008 Apr.
  - Accession 50155 (17 cu. ft.), 2009 Jan Sept.
  - Accession 50882 (15 cu. ft.), 2009 Nov-2010 June.
  - Accession 51364 (46 cu. ft.), 2010 Sept-2012 Nov.
  - Accession 51781 (40 cu. ft.), 2009 Nov-2015 Jan.
  - Accession 53296 (18 cu. ft.), 2015 Jan-2016 Oct.